Lyn Tornabene Papers, 1952-2007 (bulk 1961-1989)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Lyn Tornabene Papers, 1952-2007 (bulk 1961-1989)
MS 411
Tornabene, Lyn
This collection is comprised of journalist and author Lyn Tornabene's personal documents, correspondence, publications, manuscripts, photographs, and audio interviews. The bulk of the material dates from 1961-1989.
3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Box 3, Tapes 4-10 are restricted.
Biographical Note
Lyn Tornabene was born October 13, 1930, in Williamsport, PA. In 1952, she graduated with a B.A. in English from Penn State and soon thereafter moved to Manhattan where she soon worked in the editorial departments of Good Housekeeping, Ladies Home Journal, and Cosmopolitan. In 1960, she published her first article with by-lined articles appearing regularly in Cosmopolitan, Ladies Home Journal, McCall's, Woman's Day, Family Circle, and Good Housekeeping. She authored a popular column for Cosmopolitan which ran between the 1960s – 1970s titled "Lunch Date" as well as a regularly published column for McCall's in the 1960s titled "Walking With". Her articles primarily centered on social commentaries and celebrity profiles including interviews with top celebrities from the period such as Federico Fellini, Stanley Kubrick, Gene Kelly, Cher, Warren Beatty, Bruce Willis, Oprah Winfrey, and many others.
She was the author of several books including I Passed as a Teenager (1966), What's a Jewish Girl? (1967), and Long Live the King: A Biography of Clark Gable (1977). The latter was a major Literary Guild selection and was condensed by Reader's Digest. Throughout her career, she gave many talks on interviewing, writing, editing, and dealing with New York Agents and appeared on major television shows including The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson, The Today Show, and What's My Line? She was married for fifty years to art publisher Frank Tornanbene and had one daughter. She resides in Tucson, and contributes to the advancement of the arts.
Organization
The Lyn Tornabene papers is organized into 7 series.
Series 1: Personal Files,1952-2004
Series 2: Correspondence,1967-2007
Series 3: Manuscripts,1961-1989
Series 4: Published Materials,1958-2000
Series 5: Photographs,circa 1952-2004 (bulk circa 1962-1972)
Series 6: Audio Recordings,1974-1991
Series 7: Oversize Materials,circa 1962-1967
Access Terms
Tornabene, Lyn, -- Archives.
Tornabene, Lyn, -- Correspondence.
Gable, Clark, 1901-1960.
Authors -- Archives.
Journalists--1960-1980.
Journalist -- Correspondence.
Performing arts -- Interviews.
Politicians--United States—Interviews.
Container List
- Series 1: Personal Files, 1952-2004
  - General, 1952-1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inscribed Books, 1962, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publication Agreement/ Royalty Statements, 1966-1969, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publicity, 1954-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, 1974-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tornabene, Lyn Vs. Proctor ans Gamble Company, et al, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1967-2007
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, 1967-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1954-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Plaques, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Plaques, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lunch Date Memos, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McCall's Magazine, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - What's a Jewish Girl?, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Manuscripts, 1961-1989
  - Advantage Miss Page, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Benny, Jack Interview, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fellini, Federico Lunch Date, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Female Faults: Is One of These Yours?, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Frost, David Paradine Interview, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gimbel, Peter Interview, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Grant, Cary Lunch Date, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Helen, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Helen, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - How to Interpret Local Movie and Theater Ads, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - How to Interpret Your Job Interviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - I Passed as a Teenager (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - I Passed as a Teenager (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Interview Research Materials, 1949-1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Koch, Ed Interview, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kubrick, Stanley, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lemmon, Jack Lunch Date, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Long Live the King Background Research, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mastroianni, Marcello Lunch Date, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Moon People, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - On Your Feet, Lysistrata, It's Time to go Where the Men Are, 1964 November 05 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Palmer, Arnold Interview, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sonny, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Title One, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - War Wives, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - What Goes on at the Betty Ford Center, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - What’s a Jewish Girl?, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Winfrey, Oprah Interview, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series 4: Published Materials, 1958-2000
  - Cosmopolitan, 1958-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1981-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Esquire, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Family Circle, 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General, 1963-2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - McCalls, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania State College, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Woman’s Day, 1977-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Series 5: Photographs, circa 1952-2004 (bulk circa 1962-1972)
  - gable, Clark undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - General (1 of 2), circa 1962-2004 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General (2 of 2), circa 1962-2004 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Tornabene, Lyn circa 1952-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series 6: Audio Recordings, 1974-1991
  Box 3, tapes 4-10 are restricted.
  - Brokaw, Tom, Part 1, Microcassette, 1982 (Box 3, Tape 1)
  - Brokaw, Tom, Part 2, Microcassette, 1982 (Box 3, Tape 2)
  - Brokaw, Tom, Part 3, Microcassette, 1982 (Box 3, Tape 3)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 1, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 4)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 2, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 5)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 3, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 6)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 4, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 7)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 5, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 8)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 6, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 9)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Part 7, Audiocassette, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 10)
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, Compact Disc, (RESTRICTED) undated (Box 3, Tape 10 A)
    Compact Disc that contains content from box 3, tapes 4-10.
  - Cain, Michael, Part 1, Audiocassette, 1980 (Box 3, Tape 11)
  - Cain, Michael, Part 2, Audiocassette, 1980 (Box 3, Tape 12)
  - Cher, Audiocassette, 1974 April 09 (Box 3, Tape 13)
  - Cher, Part 1-2, Microcassette, 1988 (Box 3, Tape 14)
  - Cher, Part 3, Microcassette, 1988 (Box 3, Tape 15)
  - Cronkite, Walter, Audiocassette, 1977 November 17 (Box 3, Tape 16)
  - Cronkite, Walter, Audiocassette, 1977 November 20 (Box 3, Tape 17)
  - Cronkite, Walter, Audiocassette, 1978 January 13 (Box 3, Tape 18)
  - Side A – Fonda, Jane, Side B- Graham, Billy, Microcassette, undated (Box 4, Tape 1)
  - Gimbel, Paul, Part 1, Audiocassette, undated (Box 4, Tape 2)
  - Gimbel, Paul, Part 2, Audiocassette, undated (Box 4, Tape 3)
  - Kennedy, Joan, Part 1, Audiocassette, 1978 April 03 (Box 4, Tape 4)
  - Kennedy, Joan, Part 2, Audiocassette, 1978 April 03 (Box 4, Tape 5)
  - Kennedy, Joan, Part 3, Audiocassette, 1978 April 03 (Box 4, Tape 6)
  - Klein, Calvin, Part 1, Microcassette, 1985 (Box 4, Tape 7)
  - Klein, Calvin, Part 2-3, Microcassette, 1985 (Box 4, Tape 8)
  - Koch, Ed, Part 1, Microcassette, 1981 April 01 (Box 4, Tape 9)
  - Koch, Ed, Part 2, Microcassette, 1981 April 01 (Box 4, Tape 10)
  - Koch, Ed, Part 2, Microcassette, 1981 April 20 (Box 4, Tape 11)
  - Koch, Ed, Part 2, Microcassette, 1981 May 12 (Box 4, Tape 12)
  - Koch, Ed, Part 2, Microcassette, 1981 May 13 (Box 4, Tape 13)
  - Koch, Ed, Microcassette, 1981 (Box 4, Tape 14)
  - Koch, Ed, Microcassette, 1981 (Box 4, Tape 15)
  - Kristofferson, Kris, Part 1, Microcassette, 1984 (Box 4, Tape 16)
  - Kristofferson, Kris, Part 2, Microcassette, 1984 (Box 4, Tape 17)
  - Lauren, Ralph, Part 1, Microcassette, 1986 October 14 (Box 4, Tape 18)
  - Lauren, Ralph, Part 2, Microcassette, 1986 October 14 (Box 4, Tape 19)
  - Moore, Dudley, Part 1, Microcassette, 1982 (Box 5, Tape 1)
  - Moore, Dudley, Part 2, Microcassette, 1982 (Box 5, Tape 2)
  - Moore, Dudley, Audiocassette, 1982 (Box 5, Tape 3)
  - Moore, Roger, 1980 June (Box 5, Tape 4)
  - Parton, Dolly, Microcassette, undated (Box 5, Tape 5)
  - Rivera, Geraldo, Part 1, Microcassette, 1988 (Box 5, Tape 6)
  - Rivera, Geraldo, Part 2, Microcassette, 1988 (Box 5, Tape 7)
  - Scheider, Roy, Part 1, Microcassette, 1983 March (Box 5, Tape 8)
  - Scheider, Roy, Part 2, Microcassette, 1983 March (Box 5, Tape 9)
  - Schwarzlose, John, Microcassette, 1980 (Box 5, Tape 10)
  - Streep, Meryl, Part 1, Microcassette, undated (Box 5, Tape 11)
  - Streep, Meryl, Part 2, Microcassette, undated (Box 5, Tape 12)
  - Willis, Bruce, Part 1, Microcassette, 1991 February (Box 5, Tape 13)
  - Willis, Bruce, Part 2, Microcassette, 1991 February (Box 5, Tape 14)
  - Winfrey, Oprah, Part 1, Microcassette, 1986 (Box 5, Tape 15)
  - Winfrey, Oprah, Part 2, Microcassette, 1986 (Box 5, Tape 16)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 5, Tape 17-24)
- Series 7: Oversize Materials, circa 1962-1967
  - Oversize Photographs, circa 1962-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lyn Tornabene Interview with Henry Morgan, ¼" Reel to Reel, 1966 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Framed Poster – In celebration: the 50th Anniversary of the Literary Guild, undated (Item 1)
  - Framed Poster – Lyn Tornabene as Scarlet O’Hara in GWTW, undated (Item 2)
  - Mounted Article – How I made Jean – Claude Killy the World’s Champion Skier, undated (Item 3)